[
  {
    "question": "A particular level of government's general power to exercise authority over persons and things located within its territory is known as its ___________.",
    "answer": "A particular level of government's general power to exercise authority over persons and things located within its territory is known as its <strong>jurisdiction</strong>."
  },
  {
    "question": "A _______ is a law of local authority, sometimes known as an ordinance.",
    "answer": "A <strong>bylaw</strong> is a law made by a local authority, sometimes known as an ordinance."
  },
  {
    "question": "A municipality is required to adopt an official community plan for any land within its area of jurisdiction.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "A municipality is required to adopt an official community plan for any land within its area of jurisdiction.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />A municipality may, but is not obligated to, adopt an official community plan for any land within its area of jurisdiction."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is <strong>zoning</strong>?",
    "answer": "Zoning is the division of a region into separate districts with different regulations for land use."
  },
  {
    "question": "Common restrictions contained in a zoning bylaw include set-back and height requirements for buildings on a given lot.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Common restrictions contained in a zoning bylaw include set-back and height requirements for buildings on a given lot.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Johnny began operating a dog kennel on his property in 1990, a time when the zoning bylaws allowed for such activity. The zoning bylaw has since been amended so that operating a dog kennel is no longer permissible. Johnny's continued use of his property as a kennel is known as a ___________ __________ _____.",
    "answer": "Johnny began operating a dog kennel on his property in 1990, a time when the zoning bylaws allowed for such activity. The zoning bylaw has since been amended so that operating a dog kennel is no longer permissible. Johnny's use of his property as a kennel is known as a <strong>legal non-conforming use</strong>."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a <strong>development variance permit</strong>?",
    "answer": "A development variance permit  is a type of development approval given by a municipal council or regional district to vary the provisions of a bylaw for a specific parcel of land."
  },
  {
    "question": "Any rezoning bylaw must be given _______ readings by elected officials.",
    "answer": "Any rezoning bylaw must be given <strong>four</strong> readings by elected officials."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the three different levels of local government created by the Local Government Act?",
    "answer": "regional districts, municipal governments, and local improvement districts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name four key objectives of planning controls at the local government level.",
    "answer": "public health and safety; protection of property values; efficiency, convenience, and appearance; and conservation of natural resources"
  },
  {
    "question": "In British Columbia, local governments retain the ability to regulate the form of secondary suites through the zoning power.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "In British Columbia, local governments retain the ability to regulate the form of secondary suites through the zoning power.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where a building previously used for a legal non-conforming use is damaged to the extent of 50% of its value, it cannot be rebuilt without conforming to the new bylaw.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Where a building previously used for a legal non-conforming use is damaged to the extent of 50% of its value, it cannot be rebuilt without conforming to the new bylaw.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;<strong>(2) False</strong><br />Where a building, structure, or land is damaged or destroyed to the extent of 75% or more of its value, it cannot be rebuilt without conforming to the new bylaw."
  },
  {
    "question": "Name three key permits relating to the development of property.",
    "answer": "development permits, development variance permits, temporary use permits."
  },
  {
    "question": "________ ____ _______ are charges that may be payable by a developer of land to a local government in order to raise funds for the cost of construction, replacement and expansion of key municipal infrastructure components.",
    "answer": "<strong>Development cost charges</strong> are charges that may be payable by a developer of land to a local government in order to raise funds for the cost of construction, replacement and expansion of key municipal infrastructure components."
  },
  {
    "question": "The Heritage Conservation Act can apply to a property even if it has not been formally designated as a heritage site.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "The Heritage Conservation Act can apply to a property even if it has not been formally designated as a heritage site.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False<br />For example, entire neighbourhoods may be classified in a local government’s official community plan as a \"Heritage Conservation Area\", which may not be indicated on the certificate of title of a property."
  },
  {
    "question": "A(n) ________ ______ ________  is a committee made up of volunteer members of the public who advise the local government on planning and land use related matters.",
    "answer": "A(n) <strong>advisory planning commission</strong> is a committee made up of volunteer members of the public who advise the local government on planning and land use related matters."
  },
  {
    "question": "A(n)_______ _____ _____ is a high level, long-term plan intended to guide the direction of development and growth of a local government.",
    "answer": "A(n) <strong>official community plan</strong> is a high level, long-term plan intended to guide the direction of development and growth of a local government."
  },
  {
    "question": "The _________ process occurs where a zoning bylaw is amended by a municipal council or regional district, either on the council or district’s own initiative or upon receiving an application from a property owner.",
    "answer": "The <strong>rezoning</strong> process occurs where a zoning bylaw is amended by a municipal council or regional district, either on the council or district’s own initiative or upon receiving an application from a property owner."
  },
  {
    "question": "Municipalities have the power to require that all business within the municipality obtain business licenses, and may regulate how businesses are operated.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Municipalities have the power to require that all business within the municipality obtain business licenses, and may regulate how businesses are operated.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False<br />Municipalities may regulate business operations through licensing bylaws."
  },
  {
    "question": "A(n) ________ ___ ____ may be granted to allow a specified use of a property and generally contains provisions regarding the term of the permit and requiring the restoration of the land on or before a specified date.",
    "answer": "A(n) <strong>temporary use permit</strong> may be granted to allow a specified use of a property and generally contains provisions regarding the term of the permit and requiring the restoration of the land on or before a specified date."
  }
]